Guide to the Sallie Keller-McNulty Academic Papers, 1977-2021 UA 396
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Sallie Keller-McNulty Academic Papers
1977-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Keller-McNulty, Sallie
UA 396
2 Linear Feet 2 boxes
This collection consists of School of Engineering Studies, Plans and reports, as well as related materials from Rice University and other institutions.
Biographical Note
Sallie Keller-McNulty became Dean of Rice University's George R. Brown School of Engineering in 2005. She served in that position for five years and was then appointed Director of the Science and Policy Institute (STPI) in Washington D.C.. Prior to coming to Rice she was a professor and director of graduate studies in the Department of Statistics at Kansas State University and, following that, group leader for the Statistical Sciences Group at Los Alamos National Laboratory.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of School of Engineering Studies, Plans and reports, as well as related materials from Rice University and other institutions.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transfered from Engineering Department, 2017
Index Terms
Subjects
Engineering; Universities and colleges
Document Types
reports
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Reports and Studies
  - Department Mission Statement, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Draft Departmental Report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Departmental Annual Records: General, 2000 - 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Departmental Annual Records: School of Engineering, 2000 - 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Departmental Annual Records: Civil Engineering Department, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Departmental Annual Records: CAAM, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Departmental Annual Records: Computer Science, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Departmental Annual Records: Electrical and Computer Engineering, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Departmental Annual Records: Environmental Science and Engineering, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Departmental Annual Records: Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Departmental Annual Records: Department of Statistics, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Departmental Annual Records: CITI, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Task Force on General Education (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Curriculum Review Committee Report, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Advisor/Advisee Report, GSA, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Report on the Planning Year, 1988 - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Program Self-Study Report for Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, Part 1, 1999 - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program Self-Study Report for Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, Part 2, 1999 - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Self-Study Report: Chemical Engineering (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Engineering Recruiting Survey Report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Merger Review Committee, Interim Report, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - SACS Interim Report, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Migration Study I (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Migration Study II (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Migration Study III (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Migration Study IV (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series II: Rice, General
  - Rice University, Engineering Criteria, Evaluation, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Rice Strategic Plan, September, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Rice University in a Nutshell" (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rice University, Research Administration Assessment, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "The Decade Past and Ahead," Board of Trustees, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Intellectual Development of Rice Undergraduates in Urban Houston, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Series III: School of Engineering
  - Engineering Review Committee, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - School of Engineering, Advancement Committee, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - School of Engineering, Strategic Plan, 1998 - 2012 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - School of Engineering, External Review, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - School of Engineering, Budget Narrative, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Brown School of Engineering, Strategic Planning Workshop, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Undergraduate Program in Civil Engineering (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Gifts to the School of Engineering (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Engineering Program Development Log, 1999 - 2003 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Teaching Laboratory Programs in Natural Science and Engineering (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Coordinating Laboratory Courses Across Engineering and Science Curricula (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - NSF Recognition Award Proposal (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Bioengineers as Professional Communicators," Report to Rice University, Part I, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Bioengineers as Professional Communicators," Report to Rice University, Part II, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Bioengineers as Professional Communicators," Report to Rice University, Part III, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Amy Ballew, "Exploring Gender Differences in Reactions to Engineering Pedagogy" (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Series IV: General
  - Career Services Center, "Post-Graduate Survey", 2001 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Problem Solving Techniques and Assessment Practices, Part I (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Problem Solving Techniques and Assessment Practices, Part II (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Summary of the C. E. Program: Undergraduate Focus Group interview with Seniors, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - ME and MS Undergraduate Information (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Current GRB SofE Finances and Projects (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Task Force on Quality Education, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Women's Experiences in College Engineering Project, Executive Summary and Student Survey Data (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Language Proficiency Requirement, Undergraduate Curriculum Committee Motion (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Compliance Briefing for Research Faculty, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Curriculum for Deep Understanding, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Energy and Environment Initiative Workshop, Leader's Notes (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Task Force on Information Technology (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Bioengineering Program (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Project Pitches and Teamwork (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - ASEE Membership (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Retirement Planning and Benefits (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Re: Chairs (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Equipment Requests for FY00 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Miscellaneous Papers (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Cain Project Video (VHS Tape), Spring, 2001 (Box 1, Tape 1)
  - Gardiner Symonds Teaching Laboratory (VHS Tape) (Box 1, Tape 2)
- Series V: Plans and Studies, Non-Rice
  - "Assessing the Capacity of the U.S. Engineering Research Enterprise" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - College and University Chief Academic Officers Survey, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Criteria for Accrediting Programs in Engineering in the U.S., 1993 - 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Criteria for Accrediting Engineering Programs, 2003 - 2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Evaluation of the Technology Workforce Development Grants Program (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Major Issues in Engineering Education (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - NSF: Strategic Plan, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - NSF: Survey of Earned Doctorates (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Learning and Understanding: Improving Advanced Study of Mathematics and Science in U.S. High Schools (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - National Academy of Engineering: Understanding the Design Space and Exploiting the Opportunities (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - NRC's Center for Information: Project Information (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board, Agenda Materials, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - U.S. Department of Education: Charting the Future of U.S. Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - U.S.Department of Education: Strategic Plan, 2002 - 2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)